Hello, and welcome back.
In this video, we'll take a look
at what's new with Redis JSON.
The big news is that you
can now efficiently query
and index your JSON
documents in Redis.
I want to revisit my previous
challenge of organizing
my favorite food
trucks in Oakland,
but this time let's add some
extra spice with JSON path
syntax and querying
documents with Redis search.
Tuck in, and let's get started
To start, we'll fire up
a Redis Stack instance,
which supports JSON, indexing,
queries, and quite a bit more.
We'll also be using
RedisInsight, the Redis GUI,
in these demos.
Let's first check out the
JSON we'll be working with.
Our food trucks have been busy.
Each food truck JSON
object, known as a vendor,
has a name, an array
of cuisines offered,
a primary cuisine,
and an address.
There are events
about town that have
a number of attending
vendors, a start and end time,
and an associated location ID.
Lastly, there are locations that
host events for the vendors.
Locations contain
an address object
with coordinates providing
the longitude and latitude.
We can use these
three JSON object
types to discover
which food trucks will
be at certain locations
during specific events.
Let's start by inserting
a new vendor JSON
object into our Redis instance.
Our new vendor is
one of my favorites--
Tacos Mi Rancho.
Here's the JSON object.
We haven't inserted any
event for Tacos Mi Rancho
to attend yet.
We'll do that in a bit.
I'll call JSON.SET
followed by a key name.
I'll use the format truck
colon and a unique ID number
for each vendor.
This is a new document.
So I'll be storing
it at the root path.
I'll do this by
setting the path option
to the dollar sign followed
by the JSON document
in single quotes.
Now we'll add
another JSON document
that we'll use to store
details about a location.
Here's a location JSON object
representing the San Francisco
International Airport.
We'll store the entire
JSON document in Redis
in the same manner we used
with the previous truck object.
Only this time, the key
name will be location:23.
Finally, to bring
everything together,
we'll create a third document
containing an event object.
This object contains a location
ID, start and end dates,
and the number of
vendors attending.
Let's create an event at
SFO on the 14th of July
starting at 10:30 AM
and ending at 2:00 PM.
I'm converting the
start time and end
time to Unix timestamps,
so we can query the dates.
Now, we need to update
our vendors that
have the events within
their object populated
with all of the events
that they are attending.
Since the events property
within the vendor is an array,
I'll use an array
append function.
I'll call JSON.ARRAPPEND,
truck:42, the JSON path,
$.events, and lastly,
the idea of the event.
Events also need to take
place at a location.
Fortunately, we
have JSON documents
representing various locations
within the Bay Area that
will host the food trucks.
Here's the JSON document
for our location.
Notice the info object
within containing the address
information and coordinates.
Redis JSON has no problem
storing embedded objects--
a vast improvement
over storing data
as traditional flat hashes.
Now, each event must
have a location,
so I'll insert the location
ID into the event JSON with
JSON.SET, event:11,
$.location_id.
I've shown you how to
create and manipulate
JSON documents in Redis with the
newest version of Redis JSON.
But did you know you can also
index and query your JSON data?
RediSearch, another
component of Redis Stack,
allows us to index data
within our JSON documents
and perform queries over
a collection of documents.
I'll show you how
to do just that.
I'm using Redis Stack, so
RediSearch is already installed
and ready to go.
I'm going to create an
index on a few select fields
within my JSON data structure.
This means I search using
terms that I would expect
to find within these fields.
I want to search for a vendor's
name, a particular cuisine,
locations of events near
me, or maybe events that
have more than five
food trucks, so we can
enjoy some culinary variety.
To do this, we'll want to create
search indexes on the vendor
and event documents.
I'll start with the vendors.
To create an index
on all food trucks,
I'll call FT.CREATE
followed by a name.
I'll call it idx:truck.
ON JSON tells RediSearch that
will be indexing and searching
through JSON documents.
PREFIX 1 truck colon
instructs RediSearch
to look inside all documents
of the key prefix truck colon.
This means that all subsequent
vendor documents should also
have the truck colon key prefix.
SCHEMA tells RediSearch to
create indexes with ensuing
property and search type pairs.
$.name AS name TEXT allows us
to search the name properties
as text under the
search field name.
SORTABLE means we'll
receive the return search
results in a sortable list.
The next line is a
bit more complex.
We're flagging everything
within the array cuisines
within the vendor
object as a tag search
type separated by commas.
So as an example, if we had
a cuisines array containing
BBQ, barbecue, and Texas, all
three will be counted as tags.
Now, I'll demonstrate
searching using
the index we just created.
I'll look for the
food truck we created
by their name, Tacos Mi Rancho.
Since they have
the key, truck:42,
RediSearch will have included
this document in the index
based on the truck colon prefix.
I'll call FT.SEARCH, the index,
idx:truck, then the query.
Since I'll be
searching for a name,
I'll use @name to indicate I
want to search within the name
field of the JSON entries.
I'll enter the word
tacos as the search term.
And I've received the vendor
object for Tacos Mi Rancho.
If I want to search using a
phrase with multiple words,
I'll want to wrap the entire
query in single quotes
like this.
Next, I'll search
for a tag data type.
Remember that we set the
cuisines array in our vendor
documents as a list of
tags in our search index.
This allows me to enter one of
the tag words as a search term.
I'll call FT.SEARCH, idx:truck,
followed by the cuisines field.
I want to find
vendors with a tag
word Peruvian within
their cuisines array.
So I'll enter Peruvian
in curly braces.
Note that when searching
tags, the term must
be wrapped in curly braces.
Now, I want to create an index
for our event JSON documents.
For this index, I'll be
searching through all keys
with the prefix event colon.
The SCHEMA will have three
fields to search through--
$.assigned_vendors AS
assigned_underscore NUMERIC
SORTABLE.
This indicates that assigned
vendors will be a number.
I'll want to be able
to sort the results,
so I'm including the
option, SORTABLE.
$.name will be treated the same
as the vendor object's name.
I'll set it as a
text search type,
and the results
will be sortable.
I want to treat $.location_name
the same as name.
I'll set it as
location_name TEXT.
Now, I'll try to find an event
with five or more food trucks.
I'll call FT.SEARCH, specifying
idx:event as the index
the search.
In my query, @assigned_vendors
tells RediSearch
the field to look at and 5 and
infinite in square brackets
to find the range of
values to search for.
Pro tip-- if I wanted to
search for events with exactly
five assigned vendors,
I would simply
set the range from 5 to 5.
The event I created earlier
is returned since it
has eight assigned vendors.
That's a lot of
delicious options.
OK.
That was a lot of
info to go over.
If you'd like to learn more
about the new Redis JSON
and how well it interacts with
RediSearch at your own pace,
check out our new
Redis University
course, RU204, Storing,
Querying, and Indexing
JSON at Speed.
It's just one of many courses
available to you covering
specific topics within Redis.
If you'd like to try
it out Redis Stack,
use one of the links in the
video description below.
You can download
Redis Stack, or you
can provision a basic instance
in the cloud for free.
No installation or local
configuration necessary.
Thanks for watching.
I hope you enjoy these delicious
new updates to Redis JSON
and find them just as
appetizing as I do.